Of all the lives he changed, the one that changed the most was his own.
Mr. Holland's Opus is a drama, music film directed by Stephen Herek.
In 1965, passionate musician Glenn Holland takes a day job as a high school music teacher, convinced
it's just a small obstacle on the road to his true calling: writing a historic opus.
As the decades roll by with the composition unwritten but generations of students
inspired through his teaching, Holland must redefine his life's purpose.
Glenn Holland, played by Richard Dreyfuss.
Iris Holland, played by Glenne Headly.
Bill Meister, played by Jay Thomas.
Principal Jacobs, played by Olympia Dukakis.
Vice Principal Gene Wolters, played by William H. Macy.
Gertrude Lang, played by Alicia Witt.
Holland's Opus is a 1995 American drama film directed by
Stephen Herek, produced by Ted Field, Robert W.
Cort, and Michael Nolin, and written by Patrick Sheane Duncan.
The film stars Richard Dreyfuss in the title role of Glenn Holland, a dedicated high school music teacher who attempts to
compose his own music while struggling to balance his job and life with his wife and profoundly deaf son.
The cast also includes Glenne Headly, Olympia Dukakis, William H.
Macy, and Jay Thomas.
The film was nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Screenplay in 1995.
Richard Dreyfuss received nominations for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor
– Motion Picture Drama and the Academy Award for Best Actor.
The film explores themes of high school, husband wife
relationship, composer, music teacher, mentor.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.